Mark Pesantes

Website: markpesantes.com

LinkedIn:. <u>linkedin.com/in/markpesantes/</u>

Email: mpesantes89@gmail.com **Telephone:** (518) 218-6532

OVERVIEW

For the past three years I've been a front-end developer working daily to bring designs and experiences to life. I like contributing to a team who is open to feedback, passionate about learning from each other, and solving problems together.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Programming Languages: PHP, Liquid, Javascript, Less, Sass, HTML, CSS,

CMS, VCS, Frameworks: Git, Wordpress, Bootstrap, Shopify, Woocommerce

Desktop Operating Systems: Mac OSx, Windows, Linux (Ubuntu)

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Front-End Web Developer, Huemor Designs, Farmingdale, NY — January 2015 - Present Day Develop sites based on mockups.

Create custom solutions based on client needs.

Use progressive enhancement to support older browsers

Freelance Web Developer, Troy, NY — May 2014 - October 2014 Integrate sites into CMS.

Leverage frameworks to implement custom solutions.

Take sites from prototype to functional product.

Technician, Apple, Albany, NY — July 2011 - May 2014

Hardware and Software troubleshooting on all Apple devices.

Trained customers and new technicians on software, devices, and repair.

Executed timely repairs.

Mobile Technician, Flextronics, Albany, NY -2009-2011

Contractor to Verizon Wireless.

Provided Account, Hardware, and Software troubleshooting.

EDUCATION

Hudson Valley Community College - Web Design & Programming - Significant coursework completed, no degree earned

Current GPA 3.78

- Member of Phi Theta Kappa
- Honors Since 2012

Gerald R. Claps, 2 Year Certificate, Computer Animation-2007

General Douglas Macarthur High School- 2007